Well, now that we have everything in order, we can move to our next stage, which is to develop the
game play mechanics.
Now, just like with our previous project, we can start with our main character, which is Ben.
So in this game, we want Ben to try to keep the ball in the air by hitting it.
So all that Ben needs to do is go left and right.
And when we click the arrow keys.
Now I'm very confident that you can solve this problem by yourself.
So why not pause the video and try to complete this part by yourself?
Come on, pause it and give it a go.
I'll show you how to do it in a moment, but see if you can figure it out.
How we can just get Ben to move left and right.
Okay, let's see how to do it.
We are pretty much creating the exact same script like we had for our dragonfly, except this time our
character doesn't need to go up and down.
So the code we need is when flag clicked a forever and an if.
Now, before we add the rest, I just want you to notice how often we have used this group of code when
the flag clicked forever.
And if this is super important group of code that is often used because it allows you to create programs
that run continuously with the forever and react to specific conditions with the if.
So these code blocks form the foundation of many scratch projects and are essential for creating interactive
programs.
So moving on.
The rest is all the same.
We'll bring in the key pressed.
Change it to the right arrow.
Then go to the motions and bring in this change x by ten.
This means we press the right arrow.
It will move ten times to the right.
And now we can simply duplicate this.
Change it to the left arrow and change x to minus ten.
This means it will move ten times to the left.
And there you go.
Weeks ago, the first part of it was the mechanics is done yesterday and dusted.
Pretty fast, wasn't it?